# WALE OGUNDALU

360 Vellore Pak Avenue, Woodbridge ON; Tel: 647-673-3667; Email: waleogundalu2002@yahoo.com

January 28, 2018

The Human Resources 30 Forensic Engineering, Toronto, ON M5J 1T1

Dear Sir / Madam,

# Application for the position of Associate - Civil Engineer, Structural and Building Science

I hereby apply for the advertised position of Quality Specialist- GTA, ON, Canada. I believe this position would fully utilize my academic knowledge, professional, technical, administrative and soft skills developed over 10 years working experience in my home country.

I am a foreign trained professional, working towards my accreditation as an Engineer in Canada. Currently, I am an Engineer-In-Training (E-I-T) in Ontario, 2018. I have passed the Professional Practice Examination (PPE) of the Professional Engineers of Ontario. I have over 10 years' experience in my home country as a Licensed Engineer. I have a BSc Civil Engineering; MSc Structures (Nigeria) and MEng. Civil Engineering (Western University), 2017

Civil, Structural and geotechnical engineering analysis and design has always been a passion with me and this has translated into results. I am goal oriented, result driven, productive, analytical and well trained internationally and at University of Western Ontario, with a powerful desire to succeed and work towards outstanding results. I take pride in working hard and delivering results. I have experience analyzing, designing, inspecting and managing contracted civil / structural and geotechnical engineering works, from acquisition, feasibility, conception to actual design and construction across a diversity of clients, contractors and other professionals of multi-ethnic and multi-racial background. Working as Project Engineer, I developed excellent organizational skills; set work priorities and allocate resources to achieve set objectives. I designed and supervised over 100 technical engineering projects.

I further developed excellent oral communication and listening skills, strong administrative and networking skills in my current role as a customer service representative. As a Project Engineer, I developed excellent relationship management skills working and maintaining good relationships with various professionals and clients on infrastructural projects. I can recommend project designs and documentation, analyze and recommend improvements to civil engineering works and pollution control operations. I am able to maintain mutual trust and credibility with colleagues and team and resolve issues by promoting expression of diverse views. I have strong interpersonal skills by developing positive and optimistic views about project teams. I am an experienced teamplayer who enjoys facing challenges and creating solutions. I completed over 50 projects within budget, on time.

My knowledge includes civil, roads, geotechnics, structures, construction and materials, the Ontario Environmental Assessment Act and Ontario Regulation 616 for infrastructures. My software knowledge includes GeoStudio, CAD, BIM and Proshake to design Earth and super structures. I am also willing to learn quickly and use other software.

I can analyze, design and supervise every structural component from roof to foundations. I can interpret and supervise the production of engineering drawings, monitor and supervise contractors. I have successfully done the structural analysis, design and supervision of over 100 No. multi-story structures in reinforced concrete, steel and timber on shallow (Raft and pad footings) and deep foundations (piled). I am familiar with structural rehabilitation.

I can perform geotechnical investigations, analysis, design and supervision. I have experience with Geotechnical Assessments and Reporting; Shallow and Deep Foundation; Slope Stability; Earth Retention Structures; Braced Excavations; Anchored Walls; Ground Improvement and Settlement Analysis; Soil Instrumentation and Monitoring; Earth quake analysis; Materials Engineering and Testing; Environmental Impact Assessment and Geochemical Analysis; Building Information Modelling, BIM

With my experience, managerial, creative, communication, research and technical skills, I can make valuable contributions to your company and I would welcome the opportunity to meet and discuss my experience with you how I could contribute more to the success of your company. If you would like additional information, please contact me. Thank you for your time in reviewing my application. I look forward to hearing from you.

Yours Sincerely, Wale Ogundalu (Enclosure)

# WALE OGUNDALU

Tel: 647-673-3667 Email: waleogundalu2002@yahoo.com

## HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS

I have over ten (10) years of experience in municipal infrastructure design, as well as University Degree in Civil Engineering. I am eligible for PEO Licensure and I have passed the Professional Practice Examination (PPE). I have a BSc Civil Engineering and MSc Civil Structures (Nigeria) and MEng. Civil Engineering (Western), 2017. I have an extensive knowledge and technical skills, in civil, structural and geotechnical engineering design, consulting, construction, supervision, management, operation and maintenance, related to residential, commercial, industrial and infrastructural project as well as in Building Assessment, Rehabilitation and Restoration.

# **Excellent Analytical, Problem-Solving Skills and Judgement**

- Can interpret and analyze data from different sources; design and resolve design and construction problems.
- Can do structural and geotechnical design and construction and foresee adverse design impacts.
- Strong problem-solving skills. Wealth of experience to provide the best response in a critical situation.

#### **Excellent Communication Skills**

- Excellent oral communication and listening skills to explain policies, procedures and techniques.
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills to document information and prepare technical reports.
- Significant publications on geotechnical engineering in international scholarly journals and presentations.

#### **Excellent Relationship Management Skills**

- Can develop and maintain good relationships with diverse internal and external clients professionally.
- Maintains mutual trust and credibility with clients, colleagues and team. Consulting office experience
- Can support team successes, resolve issues by promoting the expression of diverse points of view.
- Strong interpersonal skills. Experienced team-player who enjoys facing challenges and creating solutions.

# **Excellent Organizational Skills**

- Good organizational skills. Able to set work priorities and allocate resources to achieve objectives.
- Can monitor project and make changes in processes to meet objectives and improve performance.

#### **Excellent Quality and Standards**

- Sound integrity. Ensures that actions are consistent with organizational values and codes of conduct.
- Able to monitor and evaluate work quality and processes against policies, standards and regulations.

#### **Sound Technical Knowledge:**

- Excellent knowledge in geotechnical, transportation, structural, construction and materials specialties.
- Knowledge of Ontario Environmental Assessment Act, Ontario Regulation 616 for infrastructures.
- Knowledge of software like GeoStudio, CAD, Proshake, STADD PRO to design Earth and super structures.
- Experience with Geotechnical Assessments and Reporting; Shallow and Deep Foundation; Slope Stability; Earth Retention Structures; Braced Excavations; Anchored Walls; Ground Improvement and Settlement Analysis; Soil Instrumentation and Monitoring; Earth quake analysis; Materials Engineering and Testing; Environmental Impact Assessment and Geochemical Analysis; Building Information Modelling, BIM
- Highly technical, analytical, creative expert at analyzing, interpreting and solving complex problems.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Engineer-in-Training (EIT), Professional Engineers of Ontario, Canada

2018

2017

P.Eng. (In Progress): Passed PEO Professional Practice Examination. Eligible for PEO Licensure

M.Eng. Civil Engineering (Geotechnical Engineering), University of Western Ontario, Canada

MSc Civil Engineering (Structures), University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria – Recognized by PEO

BSc. Civil Engineering, University of Lagos, Nigeria - Recognized by PEO

Over 10 years' experience working as a Licensed Professional Civil / Structural Engineer in home country.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## **Customer Service Representative**

2017 - 2018

Bill Gosling Outsourcing, London ON

- Answer phone enquiries from 20 customers daily, politely and professionally and order services.
- Respond to enquiries and emergencies. Provide information to customers on goods and services

# WALE OGUNDALU

Tel: 647-673-3667 Email: waleogundalu2002@yahoo.com

#### Teaching Assistant (TA), Foundation Engineering

2016 - 2016

University of Western Ontario, London ON, Canada

- Provided tutorial instruction to 100 students. Proctored undergraduate student examinations
- Prepared, administered and graded tests to evaluate students' progress in Foundation Engineering
- Planned, developed, coordinated and conducted theoretical and experimental studies in geotechnical engineering, soil strength, soil characterization and classification for engineering. Slope stability analysis

#### **Project Engineering Manager**

1996 - 2016

Adonai Nigeria Ltd., Nigeria

- Prepared conceptual studies, maps and layouts. Performed calculations, specification, analysis and reports
- Developed technical drawings from field measurements, sketches, calculations, specification and other data
- Reviewed design documents, design calculations, drawings and Participated in technical working groups
- Coordinated and conducted Geotechnical site investigations; site inspection, sampling and data collection
- Designed, developed, inspected and monitored over 100 technical projects and infrastructural works
- Assisted in geotechnical data analysis, design recommendations and report writing assignments in team
- Prepared engineering sketches, design change notices and prepared recommendations on topographic surveys; geotechnical investigation; foundations; structures; construction; Rehabilitation and improvements
- Assisted in Geotechnical instrumentation plans, installation supervision, monitoring and reporting readings
- Assisted in laboratory testing programs; Site inspection / supervision, proposal writing and cost estimates
- Conducted materials testing, Concrete field testing, Compaction monitoring and Asphalt inspection
- geotechnical analysis and design of slopes, retaining walls (MSE walls etc), shallow and deep foundations
- Structural analysis and design of structural elements from roof to foundation for 100 multi-story structures
- Performed Construction Quality control /Quality assurance, inspection and resolving construction problems
- Prepared technical reports based on sound investigations and analysis for restoration of damaged structures

# **Assistant Professor (Civil Engineering)**

2010 - 2016

University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria

- Prepared and lectured over 500 students. Conducted laboratory tests, investigations, analyses and reports
- Performed site examinations on loss / failure in buildings. Assessed damages and Proffered solutions
- Conducted over 15 researches in geotechnical engineering. Published findings in scholarly journals.
- Planned, developed, coordinated and conducted site assessments, evaluation, feasibility and subsurface soil investigations, for infrastructures and construction. Conducted fieldwork and tests. Assist with budgeting.
- communicated investigation and findings to others and Reviewed plans and specifications to meet standards

#### **Project Engineering Manager**

2006 - 2009

Mobil Oil Nigeria Plc, ExxonMobil Corp., Lagos, Nigeria

- Planned, organized, directed, controlled, coordinated and evaluated the activities and operations of the civil engineering department. Supervised 3 new Mobil gas stations and all Mobil stations with Safety analysis
- Consulted and negotiated with clients / contractors to prepare specifications, explained proposals and presented engineering reports and findings. Assigned and coordinated technical work of project team
- Designed, developed, supervised and inspected technical projects of the engineering department
- Planned, estimated and monitored project cost, schedules and budgets, coordinated and managed construction works to target date while exhibiting good time management skills for on-time project delivery
- Conducted meeting with contractors, owners and other stakeholders to answer questions regarding design
- Coordinated with management staff, engineers, CAD staff, and inspectors in project office and worldwide

## **Senior Civil Engineer & Head (Structures)**

1992 - 1996

Ove Arup Nigeria / Bertoneng Nigeria Ltd., Lagos, Nigeria

- Supervised technicians, technologists and other engineers. Reviewed and approved designs, calculations and cost estimates. Inspected, approved and stamped over 60 drawings for Planning Approval
- Prepared structural design calculations, quantities for Planning Approval and construction for 60 projects.
- Conducted field services, visits and inspections for contracted works with over 10 foreign contractors

Program: Civil & Environmental Eng Plan: Master of Engineering Civil and Environmental Engineering Status: Active in Program

Academic Program History

CEE

Description 9530A GROUND ANCHORING SYSTEMS 9621A LANDSLIDE AND SLOPE STABILITY

Unts 0.5

065 070

2016 Fall Graduate

2016 BSc University Of Lagos 1984 Graduate Record

Basis of Admission

COULSE CEE CEE ENGSCI ENGSCI

Description
9511L DESIGN OF EARTH STRUCTURES
9518L BUILDING INFORMATION MODELING
9692L WATER QUALITY AND TREATMENT
9010L INTELLECTUAL PROP FOR ENGINEER
9501L ENGINEERING BUSINESS

Grd 080 085 066 076

SGPS Academic Integrity Module - Complete - End of Official Transcript

CEE CEE CEE

DESCRIPTION
9523B ENVIRONMENTAL GEOTECHNIQUE
9568B ENVIRO ASSMIT PROCESS/WATER RES
9702B GEOTECHNICAL EARTHQUAKE ENG

977 077 081

2017 Winter Graduate

2017 Summer Graduate

Hold For: OGUNDALU, ADEWALE OLUKAYODE

# The University of Western Ontario

OFFICE OF THE REGISTRAR LONDON, ONTARIO, CANADA N6A 3K7

Student ID: Student : Birthdate :

250940577 Ogundalu,Adewale Olukayode Apr-25 497577031



Western

967531

Page: 1



101-40 Sheppard Ave. West Toronto, Ontario M2N 6K9 Tel:(416)224-1100; (800)339-3716

http://www.peo.on.ca

Day	Month	Year
19	11	2018

Received From 100130345

Adewale Ogundalu 360 Vellore Park Avenue Brampton, ON L4H 0E4

Canada

Total Paid:	\$84.75
Tax:	\$9.75
EIT Annual Fee	\$75.00

Zuccom P. Eng.

This is an official income tax Receipt.

Johnny Zuccon, P.Eng., FEC, Interim Registrar

HST# R106733066

### **Membership Card**



100130345

# **Adewale Ogundalu**

is recorded in the register as an Engineering Intern (EIT) under the terms of the *Professional Engineers Act*. Visit **www.peo.on.ca** for PEO's Privacy Policy.

Valid to: 31-Oct-2019

Johnny Zuccon, P.Eng., FEC, Interim Registrar

This card is the property of the Association of Professional Engineers of Ontario and must be returned on demand.

Through the Professional Engineers Act, PEO governs licence and certificate holders, and regulates and advances the practice of professional engineering to protect the public interest.

PEO is a constituent association of Engineers Canada. A portion of the annual licence fee is directed to the national body.